前方没有障碍，舰长
All clear ahead, captain.
传感器读数为零
Sensors indicate zero register.
之前的读数，史波克？
Forward readings, Mr. Spock?
重力大小无明显改变
Gravimetric reading, no significant change.
空间密度为零
Zero space density.
以3级曲速前进，苏鲁
Ahead warp factor 3, Mr. Sulu.
贝塔6号殖民地需要补给，我们要尽快穿越虚空
Colony Beta VI wants their supplies. We'll get across this void in a hurry.
虚空，宇宙中的荒漠
Void. Star desert.
这词让我联想到沙丘、绿洲、海市蜃楼
The word conjures up pictures of dunes, oases, mirages.
烈日、棕榈树
Sunlight, palm trees.
我们离那种荒漠有900光年，老骨头
We're 900 light years from that kind of desert, Bones.
“荒漠”的准确定义应该是…
The precise meaning of the word "desert"...
…没有水的贫瘠之地
...is a waterless, barren wasteland.
你的想法太浪漫了，我无法理解
I fail to understand your romantic nostalgia for such a place.
我一点也不奇怪，史波克先生
Doesn't surprise me, Mr. Spock.
你那充满逻辑的大脑
I can't imagine a mirage ever disturbing
似乎不会被任何幻想迷惑
those mathematically perfect brain waves of yours.
过奖了，麦考伊医生
Thank you, Dr. McCoy.
按计划进入904象限
Moving on schedule into quadrant 904.
离贝塔6号殖民地还有8天路程
Beta VI is eight days distant.
- 怎么了，史波克先生？ - 有状况，舰长
- Something, Mr. Spock? - Unusual, captain.
探测器侦测到一个大型空间位移
I'm now getting a sizeable space-displacement reading.
- 领航员，你能确认吗？ - 不能，舰长
- Can you verify that, navigator? - No, sir.
前置扫描仪并没…等等，有了，舰长
Forward sweeps are nega-- Wait. Verified, sir.
一定是曲速飞行扭曲了时空，让探测器失灵了
We must be in some sort of light warp or we would have picked it up earlier.
把它投影到屏幕上
Put it on visual.
这个星体的主要成分是铁和硅，星等为1-E
Iron-silica body. Planet size: magnitude 1-E.
我们会近距离驶过
We'll be passing close.
奇怪了，数据库里根本没有这个星球
Inconceivable this body has gone unnoted on all our records.
但它确实存在
And yet, here it is.
没时间去勘察了
No time to investigate.
科学部，收集数据
Science stations, gather data for computer banks.
乌乎拉，用子空间广播报告发现
Uhura, notify the discovery on subspace radio.
子空间有强干扰，舰长
Strong interference on subspace, captain.
那行星肯定是电波发射源
Planet must be a natural radio source.
离开它的干扰范围
Let's get out of its range.
右舷40度，苏鲁
Veer 40 degrees to starboard, Mr. Sulu.
40度…
Forty degrees--
苏鲁！
Sulu!
史波克先生，他们消失了
Mr. Spock, they're gone.
紧急情况，停止前进
Emergency. Full reverse power.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：Nick kmdangdangli
校对：心痕依
第一季第17集
戈索斯的乡绅
舰长日志，星历2124.5
Ship's log, stardate 2124.5.
我是大副史波克，代替舰长记录日志
First Officer Spock reporting for Captain James Kirk.
进取号正绕着一颗不知名行星运行
We are orbiting the lone, unrecorded planet in the star desert.
在过去四小时里，我们用尽各种手段
For four hours, we have made every possible instrument sweep,
但仍无法找到舰长和苏鲁的下落
but Captain Kirk and Helmsman Sulu remain unaccounted for.
我已宣布舰队进入应急状况
I have placed the ship on red alert.
我们的搜寻结果表明
We've searched again from stem to stern.
他们只可能在那个星球上
If they're not down on that planet, they're nowhere.
星球表面没有人类生命迹象，大副
No sign of human life on the surface, sir.
除非仪器没有正常运作
Unless the instruments aren't functioning.
仪器运作正常
Function is normal.
继续扫描
Continue sensory sweeps.
通讯官，你查过所有波段了吗？
Lieutenant Uhura, have you checked all wavebands?
都查过了，但没有反应，史波克先生
All of them, Mr. Spock. No response.
大副，我建议直接
With due respect, sir, request permission
登陆星球表面搜寻
to transport to the surface immediately and carry out search.
我也赞成，还等什么呢？
I second DeSalle's request. What are we waiting for?
决定权在我，我要保证你们的安全
The decision will be mine, doctor. I have the responsibility for your safety.
耶格尔先生，汇报星球表面的情况
Mr. Jaeger, describe your geophysical findings for the surface below.
没有侦测到土壤和植被
No detectable soil or vegetation.
气温极高，大气有毒，还有飓风
Extremely hot, toxic atmosphere, swept by tornadic storms.
火山频繁爆发
Continuous volcanic eruptions.
如果没有氧气和防护设备
Deadly to any life form such as we know it
任何生命体都无法在其中存活
without oxygen and life-support systems.
估算他们的存活时间
Estimate survival time of two unprotected individuals down there.
不多了
Not very long.
史波克先生，看
Mr. Spock, look.
“你们好，幸会”
"Greetings and felicitations."
把我的话发过去，通讯官
Send this, lieutenant.
“这里是进取号，请报上名来”
"USS Enterprise to signaller on planet surface. Identify self."
“Hip-hip-hoorah”？【源于19世纪英语，表欢呼】
"Hip-hip-hoorah"?
这个应该读作“tallyho”【源于18世纪英语，表欢呼】
And I believe it's pronounced "tallyho."
这是在跟我们开玩笑吗，先生？
Some kind of a joke, sir?
任何猜测都有可能，德赛尔先生
I'll entertain any theories, Mr. DeSalle. Any at all.
但可以肯定的是，那个星球上有生命
One thing is certain. Obviously, there's life on that planet.
没错，医生
You're quite correct, doctor.
传送室准备
Prepare Transporter Room.
我请求参与搜查工作，先生
Request assignment to the search party, sir.
不行，史考特，我和你都要留在这
No, Mr. Scott. Neither you nor I can be spared here.
德赛尔，你来给登陆部队装备
Mr. DeSalle, you will equip the landing party
通讯装置、武器和生命维持装置
with full communications, armament and life-support gear.
耶格尔，登陆部队可能需要你的星球物理学知识
Mr. Jaeger, your geophysical knowledge may be crucial down there.
麦考伊医生也将一同前往
Dr. McCoy will accompany.
如果那些奇怪的信号是舰长和苏鲁发出的
If those peculiar signals are coming from Captain Kirk or Lieutenant Sulu,
那么他们可能已经失去了理智
their rationality is in question.
解散
Dismissed.
没有再收到来自下面的信息了，长官
No more messages from below, sir,
但我已经锁定了信息源
but I've locked on to their original source.
很好，把传送坐标发给史考特先生
Very good. Transmit coordinates to Mr. Scott.
登陆之后，马上联系我们
Once on the planet's surface, you'll establish contact with us immediately.
如需必要，可以使用信标发射器
Use the laser beacon if necessary.
- 准备好了吗，史考特？ - 可以了，史波克先生
- Ready, Scott? - Ready, Mr. Spock.
启动
Activate.
你说的飓风在哪，耶格尔？
Where are your storms, Jaeger?
空气成分和地球完全一致
Atmosphere exactly the same as ours.
德赛尔呼叫进取号，德赛尔呼叫进取号
DeSalle to Enterprise, DeSalle to Enterprise.
通讯器失灵了，我们的通讯被切断了
It doesn't function. We're cut off.
- 没反应 - 再试试
- No response. - Keep trying with yours.
发射器被屏蔽了，得找块无屏蔽的地
Something's blocking the beacon. Gotta find open ground.
耶格尔！麦考伊！
Jaeger! McCoy!
天啊，我们这是在哪？
In the name of heaven, where are we?
看
Look.
探测不到生命迹象
There's no reading.
他们就像蜡像
They're like waxworks figures.
我得说，他们可是两座很精致的展品
I must say, they make a perfectly exquisite display pair.
但也许你们想让他们恢复原样
But I suppose you want them back now.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
欢迎来到我的高斯星球，这里非常安全
Welcome to an island of peace on my stormy little planet of Gothos.
发生了什么事？告诉我
What happened? Fill me in.
你和苏鲁都从舰桥里消失了
You disappeared from the bridge after Sulu.
我们找了4个小时
We've been looking for you for four hours.
请原谅我无礼的邀请
You must excuse my whimsical way of fetching you here,
当我看到你们的时候，我实在无法自制
but when I saw you passing by, I simply could not resist.
我是联邦星舰进取号的詹姆士·寇克舰长
I'm Captain James Kirk of the United Starship Enterprise.
哦，原来你是他们的舰长
So you are the captain of these brave lads.
幸会，舰长
My greetings and felicitations, captain.
感谢你和你的船员…
So good of you and your officers to...
…来这里做客
...drop in.
实在是太好了
Absolutely smashing.
你是谁？从哪来的？
Who are you? Where do you come from?
我是退伍的特赖恩将军，听候你们的差遣
General Trelane, retired. At your service, sirs.
请把这当作你们的家
My home is your home.
我们和星舰失去了联系，被困在这了，舰长
We've lost contact with the ship, captain. We're trapped here.
我很高兴能招待你们这些来自
I can't tell you how delighted I am
我所憧憬的星球的访客
to have visitors from the very planet that I've made my hobby.
但根据我的观察
Yes, but according to my observations,
以你们的科技水平，你们应该来不了这里
I didn't think you capable of such voyages.
注意时差，舰长，这里离地球有900光年
Notice the period, captain. Nine hundred light years from Earth.
他可能是使用某种
It's what might be seen through a viewing scope
大型望远镜观察的
if it were powerful enough.
没错，我一直在观察你们地球上的动静
Yes. I've been looking in on the doings on your lively little Earth.
你看到的是900年前的情况
Then you've been looking in on the doings 900 years past.
哦，是吗？
Oh, really?
我搞错时间了吗？
Have I made an error in time?
我真糊涂
How fallible of me.
我本来想让你们宾至如归的
Oh, I did so want to make you feel at home.
原本我还挺满意这些装饰的
I'm quite proud of the detail.
- 特赖恩将军 - 是“退伍的”，长官
- General Trelane-- - Retired, sir.
现在我是乡绅特赖恩，你可以称呼我作乡绅
Just Squire Trelane now. And you may call me squire.
我喜欢这个称谓
Yes, I rather fancy that.
为什么你要把我们软禁在这？
For what purpose have you imprisoned us here?
软禁？胡说，你们是我的贵宾
Imprisoned? Nonsense. You're my guests.
你看，我刚研究完令我着迷的人类社会
You see, I just finished my studies of your curious and fascinating society.
你们来得正是时候
You came by at the most propitious moment.
我想了解你们关于战役、战争
I want to know all about your campaigns, your battles,
和侵略的一切
your missions of conquest.
我们的目标是和平，不是为了侵略
Our missions are peaceful, not for conquest.
我们只有在别无选择的时候才进行战斗
When we do battle, it is only because we have no choice.
那只是官方说法吧？
Bet that's the official story, eh?
我必须请你让我们回去
I must ask you to let us go back to our ship.
那可不行，我要邀你们共同进餐
Oh, I wouldn't hear of it. You shall join me in a repast.
我想知道你们对战争和杀戮的看法
I want to learn all about your feelings on war and killing and conquest.
以及等等
That sort of thing.
你们可是少数几种会自相残杀的
Do you know that you're one of the few predator species
掠食者之一，知道吗？
that preys even on itself?
等等
Not yet.
用击晕模式，别杀他，德赛尔
Put it on stun, not to kill, DeSalle.
“德赛尔”？
"DeSalle," did you say?
是的，我的祖先是法国人
My ancestry is French, yes.
你知道吗，我非常敬仰拿破仑
You know, I admire your Napoleon very much.
他是德赛尔，我们的领航员
This is Mr. DeSalle, our navigator.
这两位是医疗官麦考伊和舵手苏鲁
Dr. McCoy, our medical officer, Mr. Sulu, our helmsman,
还有卡尔·耶格尔，气象学家
and Karl Jaeger, meteorologist.
欢迎您，伟大的医生
Welcome, good physicianer, honourable sir.
他在开玩笑吗？
Is he kidding?
我是个科学家，不是军事家
I'm a scientist, not a military man.
别那么说，其实在骨子里，我们都是军事家
Oh, come now. We're all military men under the skin.
我们都爱穿军装
And how we do love our uniforms.
那武器真有意思
What an interesting weapon you've got there.
让我看看
Do let me see it.
嗯，我看看…
Yes. Now, let me see...
这怎么用？
How does this work?
啊，是的，这种模式杀不了人…
Ah, yes. This won't kill...
…但这种模式可以
...and this will.
哇，真厉害
Oh, how marvellous.
破坏力好强
Devastating.
这东西能用来进行大屠杀
Why, this could kill millions.
那你想从谁开始？我们？
Who do you start with, my crew? Are we your next targets?
这真是你们人类的典型反应
Oh, how absolutely typical of your species.
因为无知，所以恐惧
You don't understand something, so you become fearful.
让我猜猜你在想什么
Now, do let me anticipate your next question.
你想知道我是怎么做到这一切的
You want to know how I've managed all of this.
没错
That's correct.
简单地说，我们…我和其他人
We, meaning I and others, have, to state the matter briefly,
拥有一个完美的、可以使物质和能量
perfected a system by which matter can be transferred to energy
互相转变的系统
and back to matter again.
就像进取号上的传送系统？
Like the transporter system aboard the Enterprise?
类似，但高级得多
A crude example of an infinitely more sophisticated process.
我们不仅能够传送物质
You see, we not only transport matter from place to place,
还能随意改变它的形态
but we can alter its shape at will.
这个客厅…
This drawing room...
…是你利用那个系统创造出来的吗？
...did you create it by rearranging matter on this planet?
没错
Quite.
我明白了
I see.
- 你是怎么…？ - 亲爱的舰长
- How did you manage--? - Dear captain,
把你的问题抛到一边吧
your enquiries are becoming tiresome.
我想让你们享受在这里的时光
I want you to be happy. Free yourself of care.
感受尚武的精神
Let's enjoy ourselves in the spirit of martial good fellowship.
够了，我们走
Come on, let's go. We're getting out.
你太无礼了，你们不能走
You're being quite rude. You can't go.
看来，我需要再让你见识下我的力量
Apparently, you need another demonstration of my authority.
没错
Yes, quite.
如果没有我的力量
Now, that's a sample of the atmosphere of this planet
这个星球的大气就会是那个样子
outside my kindly influence.
你会乖乖地听话了吧
Now, you will behave yourself hereafter, won't you?
不然，我可是会生气的
Or I shall be very, very angry.
舰长日志，星历2125.7
Captain's log, stardate 2125.7.
科学官史波克，代替舰长记录日志
Science Officer Spock reporting for Captain Kirk.
我们已经绕着这个星球航行了14圈
We have completed 14th orbit of this planet
在此期间，我们一直无法与失踪船员
without establishing contact with our missing officers
或搜寻部队取得联系
or the party sent to find them.
子空间通讯一直处于屏蔽状态
Subspace communications remain blocked.
但是，我们通过对探测器转移脉冲能量
However, by diverting impulse power to our sensors,
已经使它们能够成功运作
we have made them operable,
并且，还探测到了一小块区域
and we have detected one small area on the surface
相比其他地方，这里情况相对稳定
which seems relatively stable.
就是这里，史波克先生
Aye, it's there, Mr. Spock.
环境就像地球那么温和，你有什么看法？
Peaceful as Earth, but how do you explain it?
没什么看法，史考特先生
I don't, Mr. Scott. It simply exists.
可能是人为的，也可能是自然的鬼斧神工
Artificial, perhaps, or a freak of nature.
那里可能有生命
But the fact remains that life can exist in that area.
的确，但活动范围将会很小
Aye, it could, but it couldn't move around much.
微调探测器
Apply a fine tuning on our sensors.
对那块区域的所有生命进行定位
Locate any life forms in that stable area.
就算找到了，也不一定就是我们的人
Even if we find any, it doesn't follow that it would be our people.
没错
Affirmative.
但如果舰长就在那个星球上，而且还活着
But if the captain is down there, and alive,
那他只能在那块区域
that's where he'll have to be.
我们只能尝试把所有探测到的生命传送上来
We'll attempt to transport up any living beings our sensors detect.
这不是无的放矢吗，史波克先生？
Shooting in the dark, Mr. Spock?
要不然我们只能坐以待毙，史考特
Or stand by and do nothing, Mr. Scott.
这些是你们的战旗
And this, of course, is an array of your battle flags and pennants,
可以追溯到十字军东征和汉尼拔侵略战
dating back to the Crusades, to Hannibal's invaders,
以及希腊和波斯时期
the Grecian war galleys, and the hordes of Persia.
想像一下吧，舰长
Can't you imagine it, captain?
数以千计的军人大步迈向死亡
The thousands of men marching off to their deaths,
在这些旗帜下放声高歌
singing beneath these banners.
难道这不让你热血沸腾吗？
Doesn't it make your blood run swiftly?
舰长，他到底是哪来的？
Captain, where could he possibly come from?
这疯子到底是什么人？
Who is this maniac?
应该问，“他是什么？”
Better say "what is he?"
我对他进行了检测，结果不可思议
I monitored him, and what I found was unbelievable.
- 他不是生命体？ - 不符合我们对生命体的定义
- Not alive? - Not in the way we define life.
没有任何指标，都是0
No trace. Zero.
你的意思是他是死人？
You mean, it shows he's dead?
根本无法判断他是否存在，更别说死活
It doesn't even show that he exists at all, alive or dead.
舰长，你看那堆炉火
Notice the wood fire, captain.
烧得很旺，炉灰也在发亮，可是却没有任何热量
Burning steadily, ember bed glowing, and it doesn't give off any heat at all.
没有热量的火焰
Fire without heat.
早已过时的
Mistaking all this for present-day Earth
所谓“现代”的地球文明
without taking into account the time differential.
不管他是什么，他绝非无所不知
Whatever we're dealing with, he certainly isn't all-knowledgeable.
他也会犯错
He makes mistakes.
你们是在商量下一步计划吗
Discussing deep-laid plans, I'll wager.
真想看看你们能想出什么计谋
I cannot wait to see them evolve.
特赖恩，我们没有…
Trelane, we haven't planned--
别误会，我不是在谴责你们
Do not think that I deplore your martial virtue
狡诈的军事谋略
of deception and stratagem.
相反
Quite the contrary.
我对你们的种族充满敬意
I have nothing but admiration for your whole species.
如果真的如你所说
If your admiration is genuine,
你也应该尊重我们的职责
you must have respect for our sense of duty too.
进取号需要我们，我们有任务在身
Our ship has need of us. We have tasks to perform.
但现在我还不能让你们走
Oh, I can't let you go now.
你们的到来让我摆脱了孤独
I was getting a bit bored until you came.
你们必须留下来
You must stay.
必须
I insist.
- 那什么时候可以走？ - 等一切都结束之后
- For how long? - Until this is over, of course.
- 等什么结束之后？ - 亲爱的舰长，别再问了
- Until what is over? - Dear captain, so many questions.
好好享受现在吧
Make the most of an uncertain future. Enjoy yourself today.
所谓今朝有酒今朝醉
Tomorrow may never come at all.
特赖恩，就算我们想留下，船员们也会很担心的
Trelane, even if we wanted to stay, our companions are missing us.
抱歉，我应该体谅你们的心情
Yes. I must experience your sense of concern,
不应该让你的船员担心
your grief at the separation.
飞舰上有400名男女船员正等着我们
There are 400 men and women aboard that ship.
女船员？
Women?
你的意思是
Do you mean that you actually have
比你们更加迷人的女性人类也在船上？
members of the fairer sex among your crew?
哦，天哪
Oh, how charming.
她们一定都非常漂亮
And they must be all very beautiful.
我应该向她们献一下殷勤
And I shall be so very gallant to them.
好，让我把她们带下来
Here, let me fetch them down at once.
不
No.
不？
No?
这场闹剧应该结束了，她们都是重要的工作人员
This game has gone on long enough. Those are crucial operating personnel.
- 你不能… - 我可以随心所欲
- You can't-- - I can do anything I want.
你应该了解这一点才对
I should think that you would have realised that by now.
舰长，我们接收到了传送信号
Captain, receiving a transporter signal.
传送信号？他在说什么？
Transporter signal? What does he mean?
- 快告诉我 - 特赖恩，他的意思是
- You must tell me. - It means, Trelane...
…多亏了史波克先生，聚会结束了
...the party's over, thanks to Mr. Spock.
等等！我不接受你们的告辞，我还没让你们走
Wait! I won't have this. I haven't dismissed you yet.
等等！不准走
Stop! I won't have this.
各就各位，向我报告，史波克
Everyone to stations. Report, Mr. Spock.
扫描仪能看透那片辐射场？
How were our scanners able to penetrate that radiation field?
不，舰长，并不清晰
They didn't, captain, not clearly.
我们只是将一切生命形式传输至指定区域
We merely beamed up all life forms in a given area.
也就是说特赖恩不具备生命形式
Which means Trelane is not a life form as we know it,
或许他正被传送过来了
or he'd be beaming through now.
立即以最大曲速，离开此地
Prepare to warp out of here at once, maximum speed.
噢，舰长，可担心死我了
Oh, captain, I was so worried.
史考特，准备开足马力
Scotty, we're gonna need every ounce of your engines.
启动飞船，离那个疯子越远越好
We're gonna put a hundred million miles between us and that madman.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
我在发抖，不知是因为开心还是害怕
I'm quaking, but I don't know whether it's with laughter or terror.
医生，怎么了，下面到底发生什么了？
Doctor, what was it? What was down there?
呃…唉，别提了
Well, it was a... Oh, forget it.
看
Look.
你们的武器呢，舰长？
Where are all your weapons, captain?
怎么也不展示一下你们的武器？
Don't you display your weapons?
- 特赖恩 - 别急，舰长
- Trelane. - Don't fret, captain.
我只是对你有一小点不满
I'm only a bit upset with you.
可你说的那位史波克，就是那位
But this Mr. Spock you mentioned, the one responsible
从我手中把你带走的卑鄙小人，在哪？
for that unseemly, impudent act of taking you from me, which is he?
我就是史波克
I am Spock.
就那样还当长官？
Surely not an officer?
不怎么像人啊？
Isn't quite human, is he?
我父亲是瓦肯人
My father is from the planet Vulcan.
掠夺成性的种族？
And are its natives predatory?
并不如此，但也有例外
Not generally, but there have been exceptions.
当真？
Really?
你如何惩罚他？
You will see to his punishment?
恰好相反，我会表扬他
On the contrary. I commend his action.
可我不喜欢他
But I don't like him.
- 从我船上离开 - 才怪
- Get off my ship. - Oh, rot.
- 你们都得跟我走 - 我们哪都不会去
- You're all going back with me. - We're not going anywhere.
胡说！我在高斯星球上
Nonsense. I have an absolutely enchanting sojourn
为你们所有人准备了绝妙的游乐园
on Gothos planned for all of you.
你们不能辜负我的一番美意
And you shan't spoil it for me.
我画室的摆设装潢也很有品位
Anyway, the decor of my drawing room is much more appropriate.
不错吧？同意吗？
And tasteful. Don't you agree?
不同意
No.
但总之很得当，这位先生
But so much more fitting, honourable sir.
- 你… - 德赛尔
- You. - DeSalle.
噢，真是个鲁莽的粗人
Oh, what primitive fury.
哇，真是个无比野蛮的人
Why, he's the very soul of sublime savagery.
特赖恩，放开他
Trelane, let him go.
我们连相位枪都没带下来
We haven't even got our phasers.
当然啦，我忘了不能吓到你们
Yes, of course. I forget that I shouldn't frighten you too much.
但我警告你们，别再激怒我
But I warn you, you can't provoke me again.
大家都来吧，你们不懂礼貌也无妨
Come, everyone, let's forget your bad manners.
大家畅快聊天，分享心情
Let's be full of merry talk and sallies of wit.
还有各种食物美酒
We have victuals to delight the palate
同我们相伴
and brave company to delight the mind.
来吧，医生，别客气
Come, doctor, do partake.
你可真不尽责，舰长
You've been quite derelict in your social duties, captain.
这些迷人的船员，你还没为我介绍呢
You haven't introduced me to the charming contingent of your crew.
- 这位是特赖恩将军 - 退役了
- This is General Trelane. - Retired.
但各位亲爱的女士也可以叫我：
But if you prefer, you may address me
“高斯星球上孤独的乡绅”
as the lonely Squire of Gothos, dear ladies.
上尉乌乎拉，通讯官
Lieutenant Uhura of Communications.
美丽的黑珍珠
A Nubian prize.
她参与过你的一次袭击任务，是吧舰长？
Taken on one of your raids of conquest, no doubt, captain?
没错
No doubt.
水汪汪的大眼睛，就像阿拉伯的示巴女王
She has the melting eyes of the Queen of Sheba.
连颜色都一模一样
The same lovely colouring.
这位是？
And this?
这张脸不就是那位美得倾国倾城
Is this the face that launched a thousand ships,
引无数英雄为之而战的美人
and burnt the topless towers of llium?
海伦的脸吗？一个吻便能让我拥有不朽的灵魂
Fair Helen, make me immortal with a kiss.
文书特雷莎·罗斯
Yeoman Teresa Ross.
科学官，史波克，你之前已经见过
I believe you have met our science officer, Mr. Spock.
你知不知道
You do realise, don't you,
我是给舰长面子，才带你来这的？
that it's in deference to the captain that I brought you here?
知道
Affirmative.
可我还是不太喜欢你挑衅的口气
Well, I don't know if I like your tone. It's most challenging.
你是不是在挑衅我？
Is that what you're doing, challenging me?
我排斥你
I object to you.
我排斥没有道德约束的知识
I object to intellect without discipline.
我排斥不为众人谋求福利的权利
I object to power without constructive purpose.
噢，史波克，你还是有那么一个优点：
Oh, Mr. Spock, you do have one saving grace after all:
没礼貌
You're ill-mannered.
你是半个人类，这也不奇怪
The human half of you, no doubt.
来吧，我的小仙女，和你的心上人跳舞吧
Come, my little wood nymph. Won't you dance with your swain?
来点欢乐的音乐，亲爱的
Give us some sprightly music, my dear girl.
- 我不会弹 - 你会的
- I don't know how to play this. - Of course you do.
舰长，这场闹剧还要持续多久？
Captain, how far do we go along with this charade?
直到我们想出离开的策略
Until we can think our way out.
此刻，就让我们接受他的热情款待吧
Meanwhile, we accept his hospitality.
那你得尝尝他这儿的食物
Well, you should taste his food.
吃草都比吃肉好
Straw would taste better than his meat,
水比白兰地好喝百倍！
and water a hundred times better than his brandy.
所有东西食之无味
Nothing has any taste at all.
尽管食之无味，可却符合逻辑，医生
It may be unappetizing, doctor, but it is very logical.
噢，又是这句话
Oh, there's that magic word again.
依你的逻辑，你觉得这里神奇吗，史波克？
Does your logic find this fascinating, Mr. Spock?
“神奇”是我用来形容意想不到的事情
No. "Fascinating" is a word I use for the unexpected.
眼下的情况，我觉得用“有趣”就够了
In this case, I should think "interesting" would suffice.
难道这是你意料之内的吗，史波克？
You don't find this unexpected, Mr. Spock?
他的饭菜食之无味？不
That his food has no taste, his wine no flavour? No.
尽管特赖恩熟知地球上的东西长什么样
It simply means that Trelane knows all of the Earth forms,
但却不知道这些东西的实质
but none of the substance.
他也有弱点，并非如此神通广大
And if he's fallible, he can't be all-powerful.
也就是说有东西在帮助他
Which means he has something helping him.
- 这很显然 - 一台机器？
- Evidently. - A machine?
一种设备？
A device?
某种能帮他制造这一切的东西
Something which does these things for him.
天哪，我们真是天生一对啊！
My dear, don't we make a graceful pair?
除了一点
Except for one small detail.
这条裙子也太不应景了
That dress hardly matches this charming scene.
这下就对啦
Yes, that's more of what we want.
骁勇的武士和他高贵的爱人
The dashing warrior and his elegant lady.
那面镜子…
That mirror...
是他的观众，他的自我
It's part of his audience, his ego.
他寸步不离那面镜子
He never wanders from it.
是自我
Is it ego...
- 还是其他？ - 此话怎讲？
-...or something else? - Explain.
- 那面镜子 - 怎么啦？
- The mirror. - What about it?
有没有注意到他总在离镜子不远的地方
You noted yourself, he never gets very far away from it.
- 也许是臭美 - 不是，史波克
- I suppose it could be vanity. - No, no, Mr. Spock.
这不是原因
That's not the reason.
什么样的机器才能制造出这一切？
What kind of a machine could do these things?
一台能把能量转换成物质的机器
A machine with the ability to turn energy into matter,
由思维产生的电波操控
guided by thought waves.
它的记忆库会极其复杂
It would have a very complex memory bank,
极其精密
and be extremely sophisticated.
就像电脑，但高级很多
Like a computer, only much more.
制造这一切场景的机器
Could the machine that maintains the environment in this immediate area
是否就放在这间屋子里？
be kept in this house?
我看不像
I think not.
这台机器能不受星球大气的影响
A device capable of keeping out this planet's natural atmosphere
体积应该非常巨大
would be immense.
对，我同意
Good. I agree.
- 那我就有办法了 - 什么办法，舰长？
- That leaves me free. - Free, captain?
如果我没搞错的话，史波克
If I’m not mistaken, Mr. Spock,
我想我能找到电源
I think I can turn his lights off
让它熄火
at the source.
大家不用为眼下这一切担心
Don't be too upset by what you see, gentlemen.
他的种种行为表明他缺乏成熟、稳健的思维
After all, his actions are those of an immature, unbalanced mind.
我听见你怎么说我了，舰长，恐怕我只有把你解决掉了
I overheard that remark, captain. I'm afraid I'll have to dispense with you.
你听到的只是部分，我刚开始说
You only heard part of it. I've just started.
把我的人放了
Yes. I want you to leave my crewmen alone.
女船员也放了
I want you to leave my crewwomen alone too.
- 别和他跳舞 - 这让你生气了？
- You're not to dance with him. - Does it actually make you angry?
不要接受他的礼物
I don't want you accepting his gifts, either.
天哪，不敢相信舰长竟然妒忌我
Why, I do believe that the dear captain is jealous of me.
你怎么想无所谓，别碰她
I don't care what you believe, just keep your hands off her.
噢，奇怪的人类！真是野蛮！
Oh, how curiously human. How wonderfully barbaric.
你对她的挑弄，我受够了
I've had enough of your insulting attentions to her.
你当然受够了
Of course you have.
毕竟这是一切问题所在，对吗？
After all, that's the root of the matter, isn't it?
你们为万众瞩目的目光、赞美
You fight for the attention, the admiration,
对女人的占有而争斗
the possession of women.
如果这就是你所谓的战斗的话…
If it's fighting that you want...
那就来吧
...you may have it.
- 你要和我角斗？ - 你要是有种的话
- Are you challenging me to a duel? - If you have the courage.
噢，这比我想的好多了
Oh, this is better than I'd planned.
这么光荣的事，我是不会拒绝的
I shall not shirk an affair of honour.
这儿有一对手枪
A matched set,
和英雄人物亚历山大·汉密尔顿用的一模一样
just like the pair that slew your heroic Alexander Hamilton.
舰长…
And, captain...
我从未失手
...l never miss.
舰长日志，星历2126.1，迟录报告
Captain's log, stardate 2126.1. Delayed report.
所有舰桥船员被迫成为了
The whole bridge crew are the unwilling guests
一位自称是特赖恩家伙的宾客
of the creature who calls himself Trelane.
武器不在身边，情况对我们不利
We are weaponless, powerless,
进取号成功逃离的唯一希望
and our only hope of escape with the Enterprise
取决于这场游戏
lies in playing his games.
我决定在这场”光荣“的游戏中搏一搏
I've decided to make my move with the "field of honour" game,
胜败只在一瞬之间
and everything depends on my one chance
即这场古老的手枪角斗
with the ancient duelling pistol.
噢，真妙啊，我和一个真正的人类角斗
Oh, how fascinating. I'm party to an actual human duel.
- 准备好了吗？ - 好了，先生
- Are you ready? - Quite ready, sir.
先看看彼此的胆识，然后…
We shall test each other's courage, and then...
然后我们一决胜负
And then we shall see.
- 别光说不做 - 好的，先生
- Enough talk. Let's get on with it. - As you will, sir.
游戏开始吧？
Honour will be served, eh?
噢，等等
Oh, wait.
作为被挑战的一方，我先射
As the one challenged, I claim the first shot.
我们一起射
We shoot together.
我的游戏，就得遵守我的规矩
It's my game and my rules.
如果你需要明白这一点的话…
But if you need to be persuaded...
- 好吧 - 舰长…
- All right. - Captain...
现在，舰长，你会怎样？
And now, captain-- How do you have the expression?
“我的命运在你的手中”
"My fate is in your hands."
你把一切都毁了！
You've ruined everything!
那台机器
The machine.
舰长，次空间干扰已清除
Captain, subspace interference is clearing.
和星舰联系
Try to contact the ship.
噢，大逆不道的人类！
Oh, the remarkable treachery of the species.
继续啊，特赖恩，看样子结束了
Go on, Trelane, look at it. It's over.
你的能力不再，你玩完了
Your power is blanked out. You're finished.
你惹上大事了
You've earned my wrath.
回去吧，回到你们星舰去，所有人
Go back. Go back to your ship, all of you.
准备好，你们会死得很惨，尤其是你，舰长
And prepare. You're all dead men. You especially, captain.
特赖恩？
Trelane?
所有人，立即走
Everyone, we're getting out of here now.
我是舰长，开始传送
This is the captain. Commence beaming up.
最大速度
Maximum speed.
驶往贝塔6号星殖民地
Set a course for colony Beta VI.
航线已启动，长官
Laid in, sir.
开足马力加速脱离轨道，史考特
Full power acceleration from orbit, Mr. Scott.
已是最大马力，长官
We're full power, sir.
尽快设置紧急曲速，苏鲁
Emergency warp at the earliest possible moment, Mr. Sulu.
曲速待命，长官
Standing by to warp, sir.
需要向太空舰队指挥官汇报吗，长官？
Shall I make a full report to Spacefleet Command, sir?
还不用，他们会跟踪我们的通讯信号
Not yet. They may trace our beam.
等我们彻底离开这片区域再说
Wait until we're well out of range.
这片区域的范围有多大，舰长？
Can we know what his range is, captain?
以刚进入这片星系的位置为起点
We can take an educated guess:
估算一下
At the point we first entered their solar system.
没有跟踪迹象，仪器正常，长官
Still no sign of pursuit. Instruments clear, sir.
很好
Good.
能让我去换换衣服吗？
May I take a moment to change?
嗯，你去吧
Yes, I think you might.
上交你的水晶鞋，舞会结束了
Turn in your glass slippers. The ball is over.
遵命，舰长
Gladly, captain.
真不敢相信刚才发生的一切
Hard to believe that it ever happened.
- 舰长，我们即刻将以曲速前进 - 前方出现不明物
- Captain, we're about to warp. - Large body ahead.
- 即将相撞 - 左舷打死，苏鲁
- Collision course. - Hard to port, Mr. Sulu.
是高斯星球，舰长
That was the planet Gothos, captain.
高斯？
Gothos?
苏鲁，我们在绕圈吗？
Mr. Sulu, have we been going in circles?
没有，长官，所有仪器表明我们在航线上
No, sir. All instruments show on course.
又是高斯，舰长
Gothos again, captain.
右舷打死，苏鲁
Hard over, Mr. Sulu.
- 猫捉老鼠的游戏 - 我们成了老鼠
- Cat-and-mouse game. - With us as the mouse.
又是它，无法前进
There it is again, dead ahead.
转舵90度，苏鲁
Ninety degrees to starboard, Mr. Sulu.
转舵，舰长
Turning, captain.
但没法绕开它
But not veering off from it.
下舷90度调整，苏鲁
Ninety degrees sub-port, Mr. Sulu. Adjust.
已是最大转向
Turn completed.
依然朝它加速前进
And still accelerating toward the planet.
或者是它追赶我们
Or it toward us.
减速回到轨道，准备传送
Decelerate into orbit. Prepare Transporter Room.
- 舰长，你不会是要下去吧？ - 我是要下去，麦考伊医生
- Captain, you're not beaming down? - Yes, I am, Dr. McCoy.
我要去见我们贪玩的特赖恩先生
I am going to see our playful Mr. Trelane.
无论如何，要让他放过我们的星舰
And whatever it takes to make him give up our ship.
准备通讯
Stand by communications.
史波克，一小时内没有我的信息
Mr. Spock, if you don't receive a message from me within the hour,
就立即离开此地，永不回来
leave the vicinity at once, no turning back.
犯人上前，接受审问
The prisoner may approach the bench.
特赖恩
Trelane.
庭上任何轻举妄动都会对你不利
Any attempt at demonstrations will weigh against you with the court.
这一次别想再弄烂我的装备
And this time my instrumentality is unbreakable.
你的游戏我玩够了
I've had enough of your games.
噢，多么荒谬、低等的生物啊！
Oh, the absurdity of these inferior beings.
“詹姆士·寇克舰长，本庭判你
"And now, Captain James Kirk, you stand accused of the high crime
叛逆上级权威罪
of treason against a superior authority,
密谋罪、煽动叛乱罪”
conspiracy, and the attempt to foment insurrection."
你认罪吗？
How do you plead?
我不是来认罪的，特赖恩
I haven't come to plead in your court, Trelane.
我警告你，你所说的每句话
I warn you, anything you might say
都已记录在案成为罪证
has already been taken down in evidence against you.
我来只有一个目的：重返我的星舰
I've come for one purpose: to get back my ship.
这与本案无关
Irrelevant.
我们令你生气，是出于我们求生的愿望，不是吗？
We've made you angry with our will to survive, have we?
别废话
Uncalled for.
那把你的愤怒都发泄在我身上吧
Then vent your anger on me alone.
是我带的头
I was the one that led the others.
是我开枪打坏你的镜子
I was the one that shot out your mirror machine.
你真以为那就是
And did you really think
我拥有的唯一装备吗？
that was the only medium of instrumentality at my command?
我甘愿冒此风险
I took that chance.
并愿意为此带来的一切后果付出代价
I'm willing to pay the price for chancing wrong.
噢，那么你就是认罪喽？
Oh, then you do admit to the charges?
是的，全是我做的
Yes. Anything.
只为能让进取号继续它的航行
Just allow the Enterprise to continue its journey.
- 你这个傲慢的… - 这无关紧要
- You pompous-- - Immaterial.
那些人并没有伤害你
Those people have done you no harm.
放肆
Inadmissible.
我们是有生命的人，不是你的玩物
We're living beings, not playthings for your amusement.
安静！审判结束
Silence! This trial is over.
你有罪，怎么说，你都有罪
You are guilty. On all counts, you are guilty.
根据你们的法律
And according to your own laws,
惩罚罪犯的唯一办法就是
this court has no choice in fixing punishment.
绞刑，舰长，直到把你吊死不松开
You will hang by the neck, captain, until you are dead, dead, dead.
舰长日志，星历2126.3
Captain's log, stardate 2126.3.
大副史波克报告
First Officer Spock reporting.
依然收不到寇克舰长下面的回话
Still no word from Captain Kirk on the surface below us.
等待时间即将结束
Waiting time is almost up.
按照指令，我即将被迫撤离此地
I will soon be forced to attempt departure as per instructions.
前一刻，我还以为这不可能
Until a moment ago, I didn't think it possible.
但的确发生了，我刚才很生气
But it was. I did it. I was angry.
我体会到生气的感觉
I actually experienced genuine rage.
这个实验很成功
This experiment has been successful.
很高兴没让你失望
I'm glad you weren't disappointed.
噢，舰长，你还在生气呀
Why, captain, you're still angry.
我的愤怒能像这样持续这么久就好啦
Would that I could have sustained that moment.
噢，算啦
Oh, no matter.
你最后还有什么要求？
Do you have a last request?
特赖恩，如果你认为我会乖乖
Trelane, if you think I'm gonna
把我的头伸进那条绳子里的话
cheerfully and obediently stick my head in that noose...
那你就错了，你别无选择
You still haven't learned. You have no choice.
噢，为了省事，这是不是容易很多？
Oh, this is becoming quite tiresome. It's all so very easy.
这就是你的问题，特赖恩，一切唾手可得
That's your problem, Trelane. Everything is easy.
因此养成了你的坏习惯
It's given you a bad habit.
你没意识到，但它的确存在
You're not aware of it, but you have it.
你不思考，特赖恩，这就是你的问题
You don't think, Trelane, that's your problem.
你错过机会
You miss opportunities.
就像你之前的愤怒，我现在的愤怒
Like your anger before and mine right now.
噢，你享受其中，可要是没有我就无法实现了
Oh, you enjoy it, but you couldn't have accomplished it without me.
知道为什么吗？
And you know why?
因为你是个狂妄无能的傻子
Because you're a bumbling, inept fool.
小心说话
Take care now.
现在就有一个绝妙的机会摆在你的眼前
Here you have an opportunity to experience something really unique,
可你却白白错失
and you're wasting it.
你想杀人，那就来吧
You wanna commit murder, go ahead.
绞死有什么乐趣可言？
But where's the sport in a simple hanging?
乐趣？
Sport?
是啊，杀人时的那种恐怖
Yes, the terror of murder.
提心吊胆、刺激的快感
The suspense. The fun.
噢，有点意思，继续说，舰长，你有何建议？
Oh, I'm intrigued. Go ahead, captain. What do you suggest?
我们之间来一次生死对决
A personal conflict between us.
和之前的不同，这次是来真的
Not like the duel before, but the real thing.
赌注便是一条人命，我的命
The stakes? A human life. Mine.
- 好，太好啦！ - 这就是我的建议
- Yes. Yes! - That's the idea.
- 噢，那你同意了？ - 是的
- Oh, then you approve? - Yes.
但相比这个你能做更多
But you can do better than that.
就这样用剑杀死我不够有趣
There's still not enough sport in just killing me with a sword.
是啊，这样也太无趣了
I know. That will be dull.
我们得来点更厉害的
We'll have to have something more fanciful.
让我想想…
Let me see...
狩猎！皇家狩猎
A hunt. A royal hunt.
捕猎者之间的对决
Predator against predator.
你现在就躲到林子里，随你怎么躲，我来找你
Now, you may go hide in the forest, anywhere you like, and I shall seek.
你意下如何，舰长？
How does that strike you, captain?
这主意不错
Strikes me very well.
但你得让我命有所值，特赖恩
But you'll have to make it worth my while, Trelane.
何不加大筹码？
Why not up the stakes?
- 筹码？ - 是的
- The stakes? - Yes.
我们玩游戏的时候…
While we're playing our game...
放走我的星舰，让它继续航行
...free my ship. Let it continue on its way.
作为回报，我会给你一次终生难忘的对决
In return, I'll give you a contest you'll remember.
总是绕到你的星舰上
Always back to your ship.
好吧，如果这能让角逐充满刺激的话
Oh, well. If it will add spice to the pursuit...
我接受你的条件，舰长
I accept your terms, captain.
记住，千万别让我那么快就抓到你
Remember, you must try not to let me find you too quickly.
让我通知进取号，让其离开
Let me notify the Enterprise that it can go.
随你便
At your convenience.
进取号…
Enterprise...
进取号，我是寇克，能听见吗？
Enterprise, this is Kirk. Can you hear me?
把星舰开走，越远越好
Get the ship away as fast as you can.
我会尽量为你们争取时间
I'll try and give you the time you need.
听得见吗？
Can you hear me?
进取号
Enterprise.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
你得再卖命点，舰长，这也太容易了
You must try harder, captain, this is too easy.
进取号
Enterprise.
进取号，能听见吗？
Enterprise, can you hear me?
击中了，舰长，击中了，你先得分，我认了
Touché, captain, touché. I must confess you scored first.
可毕竟我是第一次玩哦
But after all, I never played this game before.
现在我们再来一次
And now, let's have at it again.
进取号
Enterprise.
哟呵！
Tallyho!
你真是不辱使命，舰长
You made a noble fight of it, captain.
记住，特赖恩，你承诺让星舰走的
Remember, Trelane, you promised to let my ship go.
是的，但这太过瘾了
Yes, but this is such sport.
我必须把所有人抓回来一起玩
I must fetch all the others back to play.
这就是胜利的滋味，甜蜜无比
So this is victory. It has a sweet taste.
跪下，舰长，跪下
Down, captain. On your knees.
- 你还没赢，特赖恩 - 我赢了，我可以把你解决掉
- You haven't won, Trelane. - I have. I could run you through.
但你什么都没赢到
But you haven't won anything.
- 跪下，舰长 - 绝不！
- On your knees, captain. - No!
现在还那么甜蜜吗？
Does it still taste as sweet?
我命令你，你被打输了
I order you. You've been beaten.
我没输
But I’m not defeated.
我命令你，我命令你！
I order you. I order you!
你把它弄断了
You broke it.
你弄断了我的剑！
You broke my sword!
关于胜利，你还有很多要学，特赖恩
You got a lot to learn about winning, Trelane.
你敢违抗我？
You dare to defy me?
实际上，你什么都得学，对吧？
In fact, you've got a lot to learn about everything, haven't you?
我会教训你，你耍赖
I'll fix you for that. You cheated.
游戏不该像你那样玩，我来教教你
You haven't played the game right. I'll show you.
特赖恩
Trelane.
不！
No!
不，你说过我可以拥有整个星球
No. You said I could have this planet for my very own.
这次玩过头了
This has gone far enough.
你们总在我开心的时候打断我
Yeah, but you always stop me when I’m having fun.
你不听话，太粗鲁了，我们之前就说过…
You're disobedient and cruel. We've told you before...
该回来了，特赖恩
Time to come in now, Trelane.
可我不想走，我不要
But I don't wanna come in and I won't.
我是个将军，我不用听你们的
I'm a general and I won't listen to you.
够了，特赖恩，走吧
Enough, Trelane. Come along.
可是为什么？我什么都没做错，我只是在玩游戏
But why? I didn't do anything wrong. I was just playing.
我们说过了，走吧
We said, come along.
可我还没完成对捕食者们的学习
But I haven't finished studying my predators yet.
这不是学习他们
This is not studying them.
你照顾不好你的宠物，你就不能拥有它们
If you cannot take proper care of your pets, you cannot have them at all.
噢，可我就快赢了，就快赢了呀
Oh, but I was winning. I was winning.
他们是有生命的，特赖恩，他们有灵魂，他们很高等
They're beings, Trelane. They have spirit. They're superior.
不，不，你看到了啊
No. No, you saw.
等你长大了，特赖恩，你就会明白
You'll grow up, Trelane. You'll understand.
现在，走吧
Now, come along.
噢，可你答应过我的
Oh, but you said I could. You promised.
我从没这么开心过
I never have any fun.
别再胡言乱语了
Stop that nonsense at once
否则，你别想制造更多的星球
or you'll not be permitted to make any more planets.
噢，可你们看呀
Oh, but you saw.
我就快赢了
I was winning.
我本可以赢的
I would have won.
这是真的
Honest.
不，特赖恩
No, Trelane.
本来就是，本来就是
I would've. I would've.
本来就是
I would've. I would.
I would. I would.
舰长，对于您和您的同伴受困一事
Captain, we regret that the life paths of yourself and your companions
我们深表歉意
have been disturbed.
你们是谁？特赖恩是谁？
Who are you? Who is Trelane?
请你原谅我们的孩子
You must forgive our child.
都是我们的错，把他宠坏了
The fault is ours for indulging him too much.
他会受到惩罚
He will be punished.
如果知道你们是如此脆弱
We would not have let him intercept you
我们是不会让他来劫持你们的
had we realised your vulnerability.
请原谅我们，舰长
Forgive us, captain.
等你重返星舰之后
We will maintain your life-support conditions
我们会恢复那里的生命供应系统
while you return to your ship.
请接受我们的道歉
Please accept our apologies.
舰长呼叫进取号
Captain to Enterprise. Captain to Enterprise.
舰长，我们能收到你的信号
Captain, we're receiving you.
把我传送上来，史波克
Beam me up, Mr. Spock.
我们可以走了
We're free to go.
曲速下降，舰长，曲速值为4
Warping down, captain. Now warp factor 4.
清通传输通道，舰长
Approach channels clear, captain.
贝塔6号殖民星离我们不远，长官
Colony Beta VI clears us for normal approach, sir.
按以往程序靠近其运行轨道，苏鲁
Normal orbit approach procedures, Mr. Sulu.
舰长？
Captain?
史波克，还在想特赖恩吗？
Mr. Spock, still thinking about Trelane, is that it?
正为报告发愁，舰长，我们该如何形容他？
For the record, captain, how do we describe him?
纯思维模式？智慧的力量？蕴含能量？还是超级物种？
Pure mentality? Force of intellect? Embodied energy? Superbeing?
总得给他归个类，长官
He must be classified, sir.
战神，史波克
God of war, Mr. Spock.
好吧，我觉得一点都不配
Well, I hardly find that fitting.
那就是小男孩
Then a small boy.
而且非常顽皮捣蛋
And a very naughty one at that.
这个词记在记录库中怕是有点怪
It will make a strange entry in the library banks.
可他的确是个非常奇怪的小男孩
But then he was a very strange small boy.
话说回来，他的那些恶作剧
On the other hand, he was probably doing things comparable
和你小时候做的那些估计不分上下
to the same mischievous pranks you played when you were a boy.
恶作剧，舰长？
Mischievous pranks, captain?
是啊，用墨水涂女生的头发
Yes. Dipping little girls' curls in inkwells,
偷邻居家的苹果
stealing apples from the neighbours' trees,
把铁罐栓在…
tying cans on...
抱歉，史波克
Forgive me, Mr. Spock.
我不该这么多话
I should have known better.
那就再好不过了，舰长
I shall be delighted, captain.
本集结束